# Anam Soomro, E.I.T.

anamsoomroed@gmail.com | 713-315-1077

Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Medium | YouTube

### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with an analytical background and experience in fast-paced, cross-functional environments. Through a history of roles in the architecture, engineering, and construction industry I have demonstrated versatility and agility offering a unique perspective to troubleshoot issues, boost collaboration and enhance team efforts.

### **TECHNOLOGY**

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Tools: Ruby-on-Rails, React, React-Router, Redux, Webpack, Bootstrap, Material Design, Sinatra, Git, bcrypt, JWT

Skills: ORM, MVC, REST APIs, Object-Oriented Programming, Functional Programming

CAD: AutoCAD, Google Sketchup, Synchro, Trace 700, eQUEST, Sefaira, Revit

#### **PROJECTS**

Moneymoon Demo | Code

Personal finance tracking application for couples to track their financial health, spending habits and overall trends

- Integrated Plaid's API to authenticate users' bank credentials and exchange access tokens to retrieve financial information
- Utilized Redux to store and manipulate data on the client side, avoiding multiple server calls, and creating smooth navigation
- Implemented Chart.js to provide interactive representations of data in an easy, digestible format for users
- Developed backend with Ruby on Rails and frontend with JavaScript using React and Redux to create a light, compelling UI

PictureShuffle Demo | Code

Interactive single page application where users can select an image to shuffle and then race the clock to unscramble it

- Implemented modular code to create clear and efficient game loop design sequencing patterns for new and stored games
- Deconstructed images to CSS classes to efficiently display, manipulate and persist board layout to the database
- Developed with Ruby on Rails and vanilla JavaScript allowing for interaction without page refresh to enhance user experience

CaptionIt! Demo | Code

Social media platform for users to upload images or caption other users' images to playfully compete for the funniest

- Encrypted user's credentials and used token-based authorization to ensure validated access to the application and server
- Utilized session cookies to enable client-side memory allocation for conditional rendering and navigation specific to the user
- Developed full-stack application in Ruby using Sinatra for the server and enumerated ruby with HTML and CSS for the frontend

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Full Stack Developer - Flatiron School

January 2020 - May 2020

- Created full-stack applications fostering team collaboration, creativity, and diligence in independent exploration and learning
- Utilized version tracking through GitHub between multiple developers to ensure progress without jeopardizing working product
- Completed team projects with one-week turnarounds by assigning build priority and responsibility based off MVP structure

### Project Engineer - The Beck Group

May 2018 - January 2020

- Led construction, design and owner teams in the compliance and documentation of sustainability efforts onsite
- Corresponded between multidisciplinary teams of designers and contractors for the procurement and installation of materials
- Bolstered communication through applying The Last Planner System from the Lean Construction Institute to meet deadlines

### Sustainability Consultant - The Beck Group

- Analyzed building designs for energy consumption, water consumption, use of healthy building materials and daylighting
- Consulted architecture design teams on incorporating sustainable design as best practice as well as for building certifications
- Performed data analysis on post-occupancy readings and created a detailed report as a pilot project

## Energy Modeler - alliantgroup, LP

June 2016 - February 2018

- Executed detailed analysis of building envelope, mechanical and lighting systems per construction documents and field reports
- Modeled building conditions to simulate energy performance of commercial, academic, healthcare, and residential buildings
- Worked on teams of engineers, project managers, lawyers to provide accurate and defendable studies for clients

# **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School – Software Engineering

May 2020

# Anam Soomro, E.I.T.

anamsoomroed@gmail.com | 713-315-1077

Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Medium | YouTube

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with an analytical background and experience in fast-paced, cross-functional environments. Through a history of roles in the architecture, engineering, and construction industry I have demonstrated versatility and agility offering a unique perspective to troubleshoot issues, boost collaboration and enhance team efforts.

### **TECHNOLOGY**

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Tools: Ruby-on-Rails, React, React-Router, Redux, Webpack, Bootstrap, Material Design, Sinatra, Git, bcrypt, JWT

Skills: ORM, MVC, REST APIs, Object-Oriented Programming, Functional Programming

CAD: AutoCAD, Google Sketchup, Synchro, Trace 700, eQUEST, Sefaira, Revit

### **PROJECTS**

Moneymoon Demo | Code

Personal finance tracking application for couples to track their financial health, spending habits and overall trends

- Integrated Plaid's API to authenticate users' bank credentials and exchange access tokens to retrieve financial information
- Utilized Redux to store and manipulate data on the client side, avoiding multiple server calls, and creating smooth navigation
- Implemented Chart.js to provide interactive representations of data in an easy, digestible format for users
- Developed backend with Ruby on Rails and frontend with JavaScript using React and Redux to create a light, compelling UI

PictureShuffle Demo | Code

Interactive single page application where users can select an image to shuffle and then race the clock to unscramble it

- Implemented modular code to create clear and efficient game loop design sequencing patterns for new and stored games
- Deconstructed images to CSS classes to efficiently display, manipulate and persist board layout to the database
- Developed with Ruby on Rails and vanilla JavaScript allowing for interaction without page refresh to enhance user experience

CaptionIt! Demo | Code

Social media platform for users to upload images or caption other users' images to playfully compete for the funniest

- Encrypted user's credentials and used token-based authorization to ensure validated access to the application and server
- Utilized session cookies to enable client-side memory allocation for conditional rendering and navigation specific to the user
- Developed full-stack application in Ruby using Sinatra for the server and enumerated ruby with HTML and CSS for the frontend

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Full Stack Developer - Flatiron School

January 2020 - May 2020

- Created full-stack applications fostering team collaboration, creativity, and diligence in independent exploration and learning
- Utilized version tracking through GitHub between multiple developers to ensure progress without jeopardizing working product
- · Completed team projects with one-week turnarounds by assigning build priority and responsibility based off MVP structure

# **Project Engineer – The Beck Group**

May 2018 - January 2020

- Led construction, design and owner teams in the compliance and documentation of sustainability efforts onsite
- Corresponded between multidisciplinary teams of designers and contractors for the procurement and installation of materials
- Bolstered communication through applying The Last Planner System from the Lean Construction Institute to meet deadlines

## Sustainability Consultant - The Beck Group

- Analyzed building designs for energy consumption, water consumption, use of healthy building materials and daylighting
- Consulted architecture design teams on incorporating sustainable design as best practice as well as for building certifications
- Performed data analysis on post-occupancy readings and created a detailed report as a pilot project

## Energy Modeler - alliantgroup, LP

June 2016 - February 2018

- Executed detailed analysis of building envelope, mechanical and lighting systems per construction documents and field reports
- Modeled building conditions to simulate energy performance of commercial, academic, healthcare, and residential buildings
- Worked on teams of engineers, project managers, lawyers to provide accurate and defendable studies for clients

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School – Software Engineering

May 2020